Finding Aid for the Estelle Ansley Worrell Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Estelle Ansley Worrell Collection
1970s
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0808
.21 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Estelle Ansley Worrell was born in Bessemer, Alabama, and grew up in Mount Pleasant and Nashville, Tennessee. In 1951, she graduated from George Peabody College with a degree in Art Education and later studied at the Kansas City Art Institute. Her career as a book author and illustrator, costume designer, puppetry expert, and educator have has earned her national accreditation and international acclaim. Overall, she has published ten books, all of which she illustrated herself, and served as a national authority on period dress, costume design, puppetry, teddy bears, doll-making, historical biographies, and miniatures.
Worrell began her career as an author with how-to books on creating miniature costumes and furniture. Her initial success came from The Dollhouse Book. The volume set a record at the Van Nostrand Reinhold publishing company by selling out in only three weeks. It prompted a national book tour and an appearance on NBC’s Today Show. The show received a record mail response that was held for many years following. Worrell followed with a companion book, The Doll Book. Worrell’s Be a Puppeteer! Was included in the Child Study Association of America’s “Children’s Books of the Year,” and won international acclaim by the Canadian Puppetry Association. One of Worrell’s puppetry supporters include Big Bird, who reviewed her book on Sesame Street. Moreover, Jim Henson (The Muppets) and Carol Spinney (“Big Bird”) attended one of Worrell’s beginning puppetry classes while on a business trip to Nashville. Worrell’s volume, Early American Costume, was endorsed and recommended by the Early American Society, and some of her illustrations were included in the American Bi-Centennial celebration in Reader’s Digest. Worrell’s second Today Show appearance was an interview with Barbara Walters, and came after the release of her fourth book, Americana in Miniature. This title was selected by the English Speaking Union of the United States to be an “Ambassador book” and teaching tool for educating children in foreign countries about American culture. Worrell expanded her expertise to teddy bears with the book, Classic Teddy Bear Designs. This title was acclaimed the best-selling how-to teddy bear book in the United States by the Teddy Bear and Friends magazine.
Her other titles include Dolls, Puppedolls, Teddy Bears, Make Your Own Miniature Rooms, and Children’s Costume in America. Her work as an educator spanned from the Art Institute to part-time teaching at the University of Tennessee, Tennessee State University, Fisk University, Columbia Community College, and Middle Tennessee State University’s Center for Historic Preservation. She is currently at work on two books, one about vintage hats and the other dollhouses. She survived her husband of sixty-two years, who passed in 2012, and has four children and five grandchildren.
Scope & Contents Note
This .21 linear foot collection contains twenty-two folders with original ink and pencil illustrations. The contents consist of 198 ink costume drawings (three of which are second versions), twenty-four pages of patterns and handwritten text, seven pages of pencil drawings, and two book jackets, all from her book Early American Costume. The scope is limited to the preparation and publication of this book. Many of her images are signed and dated 1974 and the book was released in 1975.
The folders one through nineteen are labeled with the folder’s heading, a parenthetical number (corresponding with the figure number from Early American Costume), date of the fashion, and a short descriptor of the image (taken from Worrell’s explanation of the images in her book). Folder twenty contains drawings and writing on constructing the costumes. It is labeled with the folder’s heading, a parenthetical number if available (indicating the page number from Early American Costume), the composition (whether drawing or manuscript), and description. The contents of folder twenty-one is labeled by the page’s available information, including the folder heading, book page number, date of fashion and identifying description. Most of Worrell’s ink drawings are signed with her initials in ink or pencil, although some are signed in pencil with her full name and date.
Provenance Statement
The collection was donated to the Vanderbilt Special Collections Library in 2012 by the illustrator’s daughter, Elizabeth Worrell Braswell.
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (1) 1580s, 1590s - American Indian (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (2) 1580s, 1590s - English Explorer (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (3) 1580s, 1590s - Breastplate of Englishmen and Frenchmen (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (4) 1580s, 1590s - English and Dutch Sea Captains (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (5) 1580s, 1590s - English Nobleman (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (6) 1580s, 1590s - Traveling Musicians, Bricklayers, Ordinary Townsmen, & Countrymen (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (8) 1580s, 1590s - English Woman (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (12) - 1580s, 1590s - Children (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (13) - 1600s, 1610s - Englishman (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (15) - 1600s, 1610s - Clean Linen Shirt of Englishmen & Dutchmen (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (16) - 1600s, 1610s - Fishermen & Trappers of New France, Nova Scotia (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (17) - 1600s, 1610s - English & Dutch Musketeers (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (18) - 1600s, 1610s - Dutch Sailor (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (19) - 1600s, 1610s - Young English Woman (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (20) - 1608 to 1620 - Female English Pilgrim Sailing to Holland (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (21) - 1600s, 1610s - Female Dutch Settler (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (22) - 1600s, 1610s - Female French Settler (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (23) - 1600s, 1610s - English & Dutch Pilgrims in Flowing Robes (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (24) - 1600s, 1610s - Female English Settler in Doublet and Full Skirt (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (25) - 1600s, 1610s - Young English Boy (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (26) - 1600s, 1610s - Young Girl & Boy (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (27) - 1620s - The Robe of English & Dutch Men (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (28) - 1620s - Dutch & English Settlers (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (29) - 1620s - Military Jerkin of the Dutch, French, & English Men (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (30) - 1620s - Armor (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (31) - 1620s - Doublet of English & Dutch Women (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (32) - 1620s - Flowering Style of English & Dutch Women (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (34) - 1630s - Eastern-Central Tribes of the Algonkin Stock of North American Indians (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (35) - 1630s - Algonkin Warrior (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (36) - 1630s - Tunic of Skins of Woodland Hunter of Algonkin Women (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (37) - 1630s - Young Englishman (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (38) - 1630s - Englishman (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (39) - 1630s - Dutchman (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (40) - 1630s - English Worker (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (41) - 1630s - Servants, People of Low Means, & Slaves (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (42) - 1630s - Farmer (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (44) - 1630s - Wealthy Young Woman (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (46) - 1630s - Serving Girl (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (47) - 1630s - Young Girl and Boy (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (49) - 1640s - Puritan Man (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (50) - 1640s - Duke, Royal Governor, or Dandy (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (51) - 1640s - Pikeman (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (52) - 1640s - Young Dutch or English Gentlewoman (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (53) - 1640s - Dutch or English Gentlewoman (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (54) - 1640s - Puritan Woman (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (55) - 1650s, 1660s - Merchant, Preacher, Scholar, or Elderly Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (56) - 1650s, 1660s - New England Farmer (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (57) - 1650s, 1660s - Musketeer (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (59) - 1650s, 1660s - Young Girl in “Old-Fashioned” Dress (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (61) - 1670s - Young Carolinian Settler (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (63) - 1670s - Men’s Periwigs and Greatcoats (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (64) - 1670s - Man’s Dressing Gown (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (65) - 1670s - Country Man (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (66) - 1670s - Dragoon (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (67) - 1670s - Young Woman in Fashionable Dress (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (68) - 1670s - Young woman in Moderate Dress (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (69) - 1670s - Young Boy (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (70) - 1670s - Young Girls (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (71) - 1670s - Young Boy and Baby Boy (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (72) - 1680s, 1690s - Colonial Man (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (73) - 1680s, 1690s - Young Man (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (74) - 1680s, 1690s - Clergyman, Quaker, Mennonite, Scholar, Town Councillor, or Older Man (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (75) - 1680s, 1690s - English Grenadiers (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (76) - 1680s, 1690s - Skirt Draping on Woman (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (77) - 1680s, 1690s - Colonial Woman (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (78) - 1680s, 1690s - Winter Coat on Woman (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (79) - 1680s, 1690s - “Combing Jacket” on Woman (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (80) - 1680s, 1690s - Simple Dress on Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (81) - 1700s, 1710s - Iroquoian American Indians (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (82) - 1700s, 1710s - Iroquoian American Indian in Special Occasion Dress During Cold Weather (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (83) - 1700s, 1710s - Iroquois Woman & Backpack (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (84) - 1700s, 1710s - Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (85) - 1700s, 1710s - Pirate (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (87) - 1700s, 1710s - Woman (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (88) - 1700s, 1710s - Woman in Robe with Belt (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (89) - 1700s, 1710s - Dressing Gown on Woman (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (90) - 1700s, 1710s - European Milkmaid, Street Vendor, or Rural Woman, Immigrant to Colonies (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (91) - 1700s, 1710s - Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (92) - 1720s, 1730s - Colonial Man (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (93) - 1720, 1730s - Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (94) - 1720s, 1730s - Peasant Man (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (95) - 1720s, 1730s - Colonial Woman (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (96) - 1720s, 1730s - Young Lady (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (97) - 1720s, 1730s - Diagonally Fastened Bodice on Woman (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (98) - 1720s, 1730s - Rural German Woman, Immigrant to Colonies (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (99) - 1720s, 1730s - European Rural Woman, Immigrant to Colonies (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (100) - 1720s, 1730s - Young Boy (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (101) - 1740s - Colonial Man (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (102) - 1740s - English & French Government Officials or Clergy of Many Religious Groups (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (103) - 1740s - Sailor, European Peasant, or Laborer, Immigrant to Colonies (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (104) - 1740s - British Buff (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (106) - 1740s - Colonial Woman (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (107) - 1740s - Dresses & Undergarments of Women (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (108) - 1740s - Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (110) - 1750s, 1760s - Colonial Man (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (111) - 1750s, 1760s - Young Man (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (112) - 1750s, 1760s - Hunting Clothes on Man (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (114) - 1750s, 1760s - British North American Light Infantryman (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (115) - 1750s, 1760s - British Naval Officer (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (116) - 1750s, 1760s - French Infantryman (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (118) - 1750s, 1760s - Colonial Woman (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (119) - 1750s, 1760s - White Cap & Collar or Kerchief on Woman (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (119) - 1750s, 1760s - White Cap & Collar or Kerchief on Woman, second copy (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (120) - 1750-1800 - Rural or Older Woman with Kerchief (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (121) - 1750-1800 - Colonial Woman (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (122) - 1750-1800 - Three Young Boys (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (123) - 1770s - Privateer (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (124) - 1770s - Statesman (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (125) - 1770s - Dressing Gown on Man (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (126) - 1170s - Young or Working Men (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (127) - 1770s - Short Jacket & Petticoat Breeches on Man (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (128) - 1770s - Farmer (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (129) - 1770s - Colonial Soldier (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (134) - 1770s - Colonial Woman in “Caraco,” Right, and Fur Coat, Left (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (135) - 1770s - Colonial Woman in Dress Made From Non-Imported Goods (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (141) - 1770s, 1780s - Loyalist Highlander Soldier with Trousers (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (142) - 1770s, 1780s - Queen’s Ranger Infantryman (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (143) - 1770s, 1780s - British Infantryman (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (145) - 1770s, 1780s - Man in Combination of American Indian & Gentleman’s Clothing (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (146) - 1770s, 1780s - Statesman (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (147) - 1770s, 1780s - Rural Man (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (149) - 1770s, 1780s - American Continental Artillery Soldier (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (153) - 1770s, 1780s - Woman in Riding Gear (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (156) - 1770s, 1780s - Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (157) - 1770s, 1780s - Young Girl & Baby (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (158) - 1790s - Muskhogean American Indian Men (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (159) - 1790s - Muskhogean American Indian Women (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (160) - 1790s - Man in Combination of American Indian & Gentleman’s Clothing (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (161) -1790s - Man in Sporting Outfit (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (162) - 1790s - Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 13, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (164) - 1790s - Satin Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (165) - 1790s - Woman in Multiple Kerchiefs (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (166) - 1790s - The New Neckline on Woman (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (167) - 1790s - French Woman in Dress, Immigrant to Colonies (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (168) - 1790s - Young Lady (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (169) - 1790s - Empire Waist on Woman (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (169) - 1790s - Empire Waist on Woman, second copy (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (170) - 1790s - Muslin Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (171) - 1790s - Two Women in Full High-Waisted Dresses (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (172) - 1790s - Young Girl & Boy (Box 1, Folder 14, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (173) - 1800s - President, Yankee Pedlar, Quaker, Young Gentleman, or Old Man (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (176) - 1800s - Puff Sleeves on Woman (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (177) - 1800s - Two Women in High-Waisted Dresses (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (180) - 1800s - Young Lady in Older Style (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (181) - 1800s - Young Girl in Taffeta Dress (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (184) - 1810s - Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (185) - 1810s - Short Tail Coats & Pantaloons on Two Young Men (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (188) - 1810s - Two Seamen (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (189) - 1810s - New England Business Man (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (190) - 1810s - American Naval Officer (Box 1, Folder 15, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (192) - 1810s - Gentlelady (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (195) - 1810s - Empire Coat or Redingote on Woman (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (197) - 1810s - Soft, Sheer, & Thin Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (198) - 1810s - Young Girl & Boy (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (199) - 1820s - Varying Types of Coats & Breeches on Two Men (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (200) - 1820s - Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (201) - 1820s - Working Man (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (202) - 1820s - Denim, Billed Cap, & Bandana on Working Men (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (204) - 1820s - Gentlelady (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (205) - 1820s - Young Lady (Box 1, Folder 16, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (206) - 1820s - Fashionable Hair Style & Older Garment Style on Rural Woman (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (207) - 1820s - Woolen Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (208) - 1820s - Front-Buttoned Bodice on Woman (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (208) - 1820s - Front-Buttoned Bodice on Woman, second copy (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (210) - 1820s - Young Boy (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (212) - 1820s - Three Little Boys in Varying Styles (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (214) - 1830s - New Coat Style on Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (215) - 1830s - Miner, Farmer, Trapper, Lumberman, or Stockman (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (216) - 1830s - Buckskin Clothing on Man (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (217) - 1830s - Gentlelady (Box 1, Folder 17, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (218) - 1830s - Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (219) - 1830s - Styles from the Far East on Woman (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (220) - 1830s - New Dress Style on Woman (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (221) - 1830s - Large Cape & Bonnet Brim on Woman (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (222) - 1830s - Two Working Women in Varying Styles (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (223) - 1830s - Young Girls in Varying Styles (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (225) - 1830s - Baby & Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (226) - 1840s - Moustache, Felt Hat, & Trousers on Gentleman (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (227) - 1840s - Dressing Gown in Exotic Style on Man (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 9)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (228) - 1840s - Infantryman (Box 1, Folder 18, Item 10)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (229) - 1840s - Calico Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 1)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (230) - 1840s - Plaid Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 2)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (231) - 1840s - Shirring, “V” Design Bodice on Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 3)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (232) - 1840s - Shirring, Later Design on Dress on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 4)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (233) - 1840s - Morning Dress or Dressing Gown on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 5)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (234) - 1840s - Formal Gown with Machine-Made Lace on Woman (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 6)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (235) - 1840s - Young Girl (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 7)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (236) - 1840s - Young Boy (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 8)
- Ink Costume Illustrations - (237) - 1840s - Two Little Boys in Varying Styles (Box 1, Folder 19, Item 9)
- Patterns - (160) - Drawings - Collars, Kerchiefs, and Shawls (Box 1, Folder 20, Item 1)
- Patterns - (162) - Drawings - Collars, Kerchiefs, and Shawls, continued (Box 1, Folder 20, Item 2)